On this beautiful day, I've been thinking about one of the most inspiring questions we can ask ourselves when it comes to our difficult and even beautiful emotions.
And it's WTF, what the funk.
And I mean this purposefully, what the funk, what this is describing is what is the function of the emotion.
What is the emotion trying to tell you, what is it trying to signal?
If you experience joy when you take on a new task, that joy might be signposting that you value creativity.
If you feel loneliness, that loneliness might be a function of telling you that you need more meaning and connection in your life.
In nature, nature has a function, each part of nature has a function, and our emotions have a function too.
They are signposting our needs, our wants and our cares.
So when you have a tough emotion, ask yourself WTF, what the funk.